The battle of Iwo Jima seen through the eyes of the Japanese soldiers.
Letters from Iwo Jima is a action, drama, war film directed by Clint Eastwood.
The story of the battle of Iwo Jima between the United States and Imperial Japan during
World War II, as told from the perspective of the Japanese who fought it.
General Tadamichi Kuribayashi, played by Ken Watanabe.
Private Saigo, played by Kazunari Ninomiya.
Colonel Baron Nishi, played by Tsuyoshi Ihara.
Private Shimizu, played by Ryo Kase.
Lieutenant Ito, played by Shido Nakamura.
Lieutenant Fujita, played by Hiroshi Watanabe.
Letters from Iwo Jima (硫黄島からの手紙, Iōjima Kara no Tegami) is a 2006 Japanese-language American war film
directed and co-produced by Clint Eastwood, starring Ken Watanabe and Kazunari Ninomiya.
The film portrays the Battle of Iwo Jima from the perspective of the Japanese soldiers and is a companion piece to Eastwood's Flags
of Our Fathers, which depicts the same battle from the American viewpoint; the two films were shot back to back.
Letters from Iwo Jima is almost entirely in Japanese with a few English sequences, despite being
co-produced by American companies DreamWorks Pictures, Malpaso Productions and Amblin Entertainment.
The film was released in Japan on December 9, 2006, and received a limited
release in the United States on December 20, 2006 by Warner Bros.
Pictures, in order to be eligible for consideration for the 79th Academy Awards, for which it
received four nominations, including Best Picture and winning Best Sound Editing.
It was subsequently released in more areas of the United States on January
12, 2007, and was released in most states on January 19.
An English-dubbed version of the film premiered on April 7, 2008.
Upon release, the film received critical acclaim and although it only grossed $68.7 million (slightly better at the box
office than its companion), it was much more successful compared to its budget (which was $19 million).
The film explores themes of dying and death, world war ii,
cave, based on true story, pacific war.
The tone is emotional.